Guide to the ILGWU Records, 1884-2006, bulk 1923-1995.
ILGWU Records, 1884-2006, bulk 1923-1995.
- SERIES III. LOCAL UNIONS, 1901-1996
  - NEW YORK, NEW YORK
    - 5780/057 P. Local 22. Education Department photographs, 1939-1970., This collection consists of photographs pulled from the records of Local 22’s Education Department. Included are images of conferences, meetings, and rallies.
    - 5780/067. Local 22. Israel Breslow papers, 1913-1981., Contains the records of Local 22’s manager, Israel Breslow, including speeches and articles by Breslow, files relating to local union elections, and Breslow’s reports to the membership.
    - 5780/059. Local 23-25 records, 1922-1972., Contains minutes of Local 23’s Executive Board and committee meetings, minutes of Local 25’s Executive Board and membership meetings, Local 23 meeting minutes, minutes of Local 23-25’s Executive Board and membership meetings, minutes of the Skirt and Sportswear Retirement Fund, and some financial documents, including ledgers of general funds and sick benefits. The bulk of the records document the local’s activities in the 1970s through the 1990s, and includes files of Edgar Romney (Manager), May Chen (Assistant Director of Local 23-25 Education Program and Assistant Director of the ILGWU Immigration Project), and Susan Cowell (Assistant to the Manager and later, Vice-President). May Chen’s files include substantial material on the local’s Worker-Family Education Program, and document Chen’s organizing with the Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance, Coalition of Labor Union Women, and the Asian Labor Committee.
    - 5780/059 P. Local 23-25 photographs, This collection primarily consists of photographs by Kathy Andrade and George Colon. Photographs document meetings, rallies, Labor Day parades, and other local union events.
    - 5780/059 PUBS. Local 23-25 publications, 1968-1995., Consists primarily of issues of Local 23-25’s publication, Local 23-25 News, from 1970 to 1995. Also included are other publications of the local, including its annual reports from 1971 to 1979.
    - 5780/095. Local 23-25 records, 1984-1994., This collection contains files of International Ladies Garment Workers Union Local 23-25, Blouse, Skirt and Sportswear Workers. Included are files of the Coalition of Labor Union Women, as well as press releases, news clippings, and other printed material.
    - 5780/095 G. Local 23-25 graphics., This collection consists of two posters, “Garment Workers Rally to Defend Our Contract” and “Students Advocating the 1990 Census,” and photographs documenting activities of the Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW).
    - 5780/042. Local 25. Ladies Waist and Dressmakers' Union. L'Operaia. Publication, 1913-1918., Collection contains issues of L'Operaia, the newsletter of Local 25 of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
    - 5780/139 mf. Local 25. L'Operaia. Microfilm, 1913-1919., Consists of issues of Local 25's publication L'Operaia.
    - 5780/071. Local 25. The Message. Publication, 1913-1918., Collection consists of issues of Local 25’s publication, The Message, from 1915-1918.
    - 5780/031. Local 35 records, 1927-1977., Includes minutes of Executive Board and Health and Welfare Fund meetings, speeches and reports of Manager Morris Kovler, as well as some correspondence and financial data.
    - 5780/019. Local 38 minutes, 1920-1959., Contains meeting minutes of local 38’s General Executive Board and several of its committees, including the Trial Committee, General Strike Committee, Investigating Committee, Membership Committee, and Special Committees. Also contains membership meeting minutes of Local 38’s successor union, Local 124, as well as the local’s publication, On the Avenue, and minutes of the local’s Italian branch.
    - 5780/035. Local 40 records, 1933-1977., Records of International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union Local 40, Beltmakers Union. Includes minutes of Executive Board, Membership, Grievance Board, and Committee meetings. Also includes correspondence, agreements, election files, financial reports, strike files, issues of the local’s publication, The Belt Maker.
    - 5780/040. Local 48 records, 1916-1972., Contains records of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union Local 48, Italian Cloakmakers Union, including minutes of membership and Executive Board meetings, files on elections, notes, and correspondence.
    - 5780/040 mf. Local 48. Executive Board minutes. Microfilm, 1920-1974., Contains meeting minutes of Local 48’s Executive Board from 1920 to 1974.
    - 5780/074. Local 62. Mary Goff Schuster papers, 1912-1982., Contains correspondence, notes and other writings by Mary Goff Schuster, documenting her varied work in Local 62.
    - 5780/021. Local 62 records, 1922-1963., Contains minutes of Local 62’s Executive Board’s meetings between 1913 and 1971, as well as issues of the local’s publication, Our Union, from 1935 to 1970.
    - 5780/022. Local 62 correspondence, 1913-1976., The Local 62 correspondence consists primarily of letters of Samuel Shore and Louis Stulberg, the managers of the Local during much of the period. There are also articles, photographs, reports, and other materials in the collection. These items primarily document the activities and concerns of the Local's leadership from the depression years through the 1960s. The bulk of the material deals with Local administrative matters, benefits, garment manufacturers, other ILGWU departments and locals, political activity (at both the national and local level), relations with other unions, union organizing, wages, and working conditions in the shops. It is mostly restricted to New York City. In addition, there is some personal correspondence of both Shore and Stulberg.
    - 5780/079. Local 62. Managers' correspondence, 1941-1981., Consists primarily of correspondence of Local 62’s manager, Matthew Schoenwald. Corrrespondents include staff in several of the ILGWU departments, as well as Louis Stulberg, David Dubinsky, and Executive Director of The Lingerie Manufacturers Association Jack Gross. Also included are records documenting the work of the Liberal Party, including correspondence and mailing lists.
    - 5780/089. Local 62-32 agreements, 1966-1981., This collection includes collective bargaining agreements of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union Local 62-32, Intimate Apparel, Embroidery, Belt and Allied Workers Local.
    - 5780/068. Local 66. Executive Board records, 1922-1959., Collection consists primarily of minutes of Local 66’s Executive Board and general membership meetings between 1922 and 1974. Also contains issues of the local’s publication, Our Local 66, from 1942 to 1971, and meeting minutes for Local 30, Designers Guild of Ladies’ Apparel.
    - 5780/068 PUBS. Local 66 publications, 1942-1983., Consists of the local’s publication, Our Local 66, from 1942 to 1983, as well as one pamphlet entitled “What Every Member Should Know About His Benefits, Rights and Duties in the Union.”
    - 5780/007. Local 82 minutes, 1917-1970., Contains minutes of Local 82’s Executive Board’s meetings from 1917 to 1970, as well as minutes of Local 82’s general membership meetings from 1919 to 1958.
    - 5780/023. Local 89. Luigi Antonini correspondence, 1919-1968, 1930-1960 (bulk)., Correspondence, speeches, and subject files covering Luigi Antonini's activities, both within and outside of the ILGWU, from the 1920s to the 1960s. The correspondence documents many of Antonini's most significant contributions to the ILGWU, the post-war Italian labor movement, and politics in New York State and the U.S. Included in the collection are materials relating to Antonini's role in the ILGWU, especially in union administrative matters; documentation of his involvement in building a free labor movement in post-war Italy; items dealing with his activities in the American Labor Party and the Liberal Party of New York; and items that highlight his role in anti-fascist organizations before and during the Second World War.
    - 5780/024. Local 89 records, 1918-1944., Consists of bound volumes of newspaper clippings documenting the activities of Local 89 between 1918 and 1944.
    - 5780/064. Local 89 minutes, 1919-1971., Contains minutes of Local 89’s general membership, Executive Committee, Finance Committee, Relief Committee, and Emergency Welfare Committee meetings.
    - 5780/213. Local 89-22-1 records, 1986-1994., Contains records relating to the Health and Welfare Fund of Local 89-22-1.
    - 5780/066. Local 91 records, 1934-1982., Consists primarily of Local 91’s publication, Our Aim, from 1934 to 1947. Also includes other printed material, files on union contractors, and employment agreements.
    - 5780/153. Local 91. David Dubinsky presentation volume, May 1940., Presentation volume given to David Dubinsky by International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union Local 91, Children's Dress, Infant's Wear, House, Dress, and Bathrobe Makers Union. The volume contains the lyrics for the songs "A Measure of Cloth" and "We Are the People," written by Gus Tyler to music by Lazar Weiner. The volume was produced for the 24th ILGWU convention, held in New York City in May 1940.
    - 5780/077. Local 98 records, 1938-1970., Contains meeting minutes of Local 98’s Executive Board from 1938 to 1970, Manager Herbert Pokodner’s correspondence, and company files that document the union’s organizing and service efforts. Also included are correspondence, notes, and related National Labor Relations Board materials.
    - 5780/053. Local 105 records, 1939-1970, The Local 105 materials consist primarily of routine correspondence, reports, and minutes of executive and membership meetings. Much of the correspondence is from Martin L. Cohen, the manager-secretary of Local 105. The bulk of the material deals with administrative matters, contract negotiations, donations to (and requests for donations from) charitable organizations, health, welfare and retirement benefits, garment manufacturers, other ILGWU departments and locals, and relations with the AFL-CIO. Some of the correspondence addresses the changing ethnic makeup of the union's membership, particularly the steady increase in Hispanic workers during the 1950s and 1960s. Other items concern the adoption of children orphaned after World War II. A small amount of Martin Cohen's personal correspondence is also included.
    - 5780/053 AV. Local 105 audio recordings, 1957-1963., This collection consists of audio recordings of ILGWU staff and regional conferences, as well as some film strips.
    - 5780/053 P. Local 105 photographs, 1938-1968., This collection consists of photographs documenting Local 105’s activities between 1938 and 1968. Photographs include rallies, local officers, and luncheons and dinners hosted in honor of guests of Local 105.
    - 5780/034. Local 117 minutes, 1936-1973., Records of International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union Local 117, Cloak, Suit, Infants' and Childrens' Coat Operators and Sample Makers' Union. Includes Executive Board and Membership minutes as well as Managers' reports.
    - 5780/076. Local 132. Managers' correspondence, 1961-1973., Consists primarily of two series of correspondence of Local 132’s managers, Joel Menist and Sam Eisenberg, between 1954 and 1975. Also contains minutes of Local 132’s Executive Board and Health and Welfare Fund Board, as well as a few issues of the local’s publication, Local 132 News.
    - 5780/054. Local 155 records, 1933-1968, 1940-1960 (bulk)., The Local 155 records consist primarily of the correspondence of Louis Nelson, manager of Local 155 during the period. There are also articles, speeches, and other materials, as well as a small amount of Nelson's personal correspondence. These items document the activities and concerns of the Local's leadership from the depression years through the late 1960s. In addition to routine Local administrative matters, the materials cover a wide variety of topics, including anti-Semitism, civil rights issues, health and retirement benefits, the women's clothing industry, New York City elections, political activities of the Local, relations with other unions, forced labor in the Soviet Union, the Spanish Civil War, strikes, and union elections.
    - 5780/129. Local 155 records, 1971-1972., Contains records relating to Local 155’s elections in 1971 and the investigations of those elections the following year.
  - PHILADELPHIA, PENNSYLVANIA
    - 5780/194. Local 190 minutes, 1938-1979., Contains the meeting minutes of Local 190, proceedings of the Joint Adjustment Board, and meeting minutes of the United Hebrew Trades of Philadelphia and Vicinity.
    - 5780/194 PUBS. Local 190 publications, 1951-1983., Consists of issues of the publication of Local 190, Knit Goods News, from 1951 to 1983.
    - SPRINGFIELD, MASSACHUSETTS
    - 5780/132. Local 226 records, 1946-1973, Contains records of Local 226, including agreements with area companies, as well as correspondence with those companies and union members. Also included are periodicals from several district councils in New England and Pennsylvania: Southern New England District News, Seamlines (Upstate New York and Vermont District), Garment Square Chronicle (Southern New England District), Needle News (Allentown-Reading District), and Needlepoint (Wilkes-Barre-Pittston-Nanticoke District).
  - WORCESTER, MASSACHUSETTS
    - 5780/133. Local 75 records, 1950-1953., Contains agreements between Local 75 and area companies, as well as correspondence with those companies and union members. Also included are two ILGWU Education Department publications, The Story of the ILGWU and And the Pursuit of Happiness.
- SERIES IV. EXECUTIVE OFFICERS AND STAFF, 1911-2006
  - Subseries A. Presidents, 1914-1994
    - 5780/009. Benjamin Schlesinger papers, 1914-1923., Correspondence, form letters, circulars and subject files relating to Schlesinger's term, June 1914 to January 1923. Topics covered in these materials include union organizing; strikes, labor disputes, working conditions, and other labor issues in the women's garment industry, particularly in New York City; inter-union relations; relations between manufacturers' associations and the union; efforts by Schlesinger and others to form an alliance of garment workers' unions; discussions with foreign garment workers' unions; education for workers in New York City; and Jewish war relief efforts during World War I.
    - 5780/010. Benjamin Schlesinger papers, 1928-1932., Correspondence and subject files relating to Schlesinger's term, October 1928 to June 1932. Topics covered in these materials include: communist activity in the garment industry unions; contract negotiations; Schlesinger's role as business manager of the Jewish Daily Forward (Chicago); labor disputes in the women's garment industry of New York City; racketeering; socialism; garment industry strikes in New York City (including the 1929 Cloakmakers' Strike and the 1930 Dressmakers' Strike); the Tom Mooney Defense Committee; relations between manufacturers' associations and the union; union conventions; union elections; union finances; and worker education.
    - 5780/006. Morris Sigman correspondence, 1923-1928., The collection consists of correspondence, subject files, form letters, circulars, speeches and other items from Morris Sigman's term as ILGWU president. Among the topics covered are: communist activity in the ILGWU, and the leadership's battle against a communist takeover of the union; conditions in the U.S. garment industry, particularly in New York City; education for workers; inter- and intra-union relations; ILGWU locals, with an emphasis on the New York City area; strikes in the garment industry (in particular the Cloakmakers' strike of 1926), as well as in other industries; life and unemployment insurance for union members; relations with other garment workers' unions in the U.S., Great Britain, Poland and the Soviet Union, and with the International Clothing Workers' Federation in Amsterdam; relations with the garment manufacturers; unemployment insurance; union legal matters; and union organizing activities.
    - 5780/002. David Dubinsky correspondence, 1932-1966., This collection contains David Dubinksy's professional and personal correspondence, speeches and statements, and greetings.
    - 5780/002 AV. David Dubinsky audio-visual recordings., This collection contains audio recordings of David Dubinsky's speeches and other events attended by Dubinsky.
    - 5780/002 MB. David Dubinsky memorabilia, 1910-1982., This collection consists of memorabilia, originally received with collection 5780/002. Scrapbooks, awards, buttons, badges, union dues books, passports, and correspondence are some of the items included in this collection.
    - 5780/002 P. David Dubinsky photographs, [1945-1967]., Contains photograph albums presented to David Dubinsky, as well as photograph albums featuring David Dubinsky between 1945 and 1967. Several albums document Dubinsky’s international travels, as well as his participation in events in the United States.
    - 5780/179 MB. David Dubinsky. Memorabilia, 1942., Consists of one 15” x 20” charcoal drawing of David Dubinsky, signed by Seth Hoffman in 1942.
    - 5780/179 P. David Dubinsky photographs., This collection consists of photos covering various aspects of David Dubinsky's life and work.
    - 5780/136. David Dubinsky. Scrapbooks, 1940, 1955., These scrapbooks concern David Dubinsky's visit to Europe and Israel in 1948, 1955, and 1956, and his retirement in 1966. Also included is a May 1940 presentation book from ILGWU Local 91.
    - 5780/004. Louis Stulberg correspondence, 1945-1977, 1966-1975 (bulk)., The Stulberg presidential records consist of correspondence, memoranda, photographs, speeches and subject files primarily dealing with union matters during Stulberg's term in office, though there are some personal materials in the collection as well. Topics covered include: civil rights; dealings with garment manufacturers; international labor activities; locals and regional departments of the ILGWU throughout the U.S., Puerto Rico, and Canada; minority membership in the ILGWU; relations with other unions; strikes and other labor disputes; union administrative matters; union conventions; union involvement in politics and government, especially in New York City and New York State; retirees' benefits, scholarships; union organizing; and wages.
    - 5780/004 P. Louis Stulberg photographs, 1966-1977., This collection consists of a photograph of Stulberg with President Lyndon B. Johnson, inscribed by LBJ, and an invitation to Harry S. Truman’s inauguration as President of the United States in 1949.
    - 5780/083. Sol C. Chaikin papers, 1940-1986., The Sol Chaikin papers document Chaikin’s tenure as president of the ILGWU from 1975 to 1986. Included in this collection are extensive correspondence, memoranda, and notes by and to Chaikin from ILGWU officers, staff, and members, politicians, and other labor leaders. Also included are transcripts of Chaikin’s speeches, delivered to audiences of local union members, ILGWU and other international union conventions, United States Congress, international labor organizations, and others.
    - 5780/083 AV. Sol C. Chaikin audio-visual materials, 1972-1986., Recordings of conferences, receptions, dinners, convention speeches, meetings, retirement, interviews, acceptance speeches and others.
    - 5780/083 P. Sol C. Chaikin photographs, [1940-1989]., This collection contains photographs of Sol Chaikin at a variety of events, including conventions, meetings, and rallies. Also included are photographs of ILGWU groups and institutions, political figures, and other events.
    - 5780/135. Sol Chaikin. The First Year. Presentation volume, 1975-1976., Presentation volume of reproduced news clippings.
    - 5780/203. Jay Mazur papers, 1951-1995, [bulk 1983-1995.], Consists of the records of Jay Mazur, during his term as President of the ILGWU until its merger with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers of America to form the Union of Needletrades, Industrial, and Textile Employees (UNITE) in 1995. Included in Mazur’s files are alphabetical subject files which contain correspondence, memoranda, notes, testimonies, news clippings, and other printed material on persons, organizations, and topics relating to the work of the ILGWU. Also, these papers include correspondence files, as well as records documenting Mazur’s work on the AFL-CIO Executive Council and the ILGWU’s General Executive Board.
  - Subseries B. Other Officers and Staff, 1911-2006
    - 5780/212 MB. Myrtle Banks memorabilia, 1975-1990., This collection contains a variety of ILGWU and Union Label memorabilia, including pins, fabrics, pot holders, and a bag. Also included are clippings, certificates, and other materials documenting Myrtle Banks’ work with the ILGWU.
    - 5780/212 P. Myrtle Banks photographs, 1966-1987., This collection includes photographs of Myrtle Banks’ retirement party in 1984, events at the City of Hope medical center, local union meetings, and ILGWU conventions.
    - 5780/198. Martin Berger papers, 1948-2006., This collection consists of photographs, correspondence, and papers from the records of ILGWU officer Martin Berger.
    - 5780/210. Muzaffar Chishti papers, 1991-1995., This collection consists of Muzaffar Chishti’s Industrial Development and Labor-Management files, 1991-1995. Most records pertain to Chishti’s work with the Council on American Fashion.
    - 5780/097. Susan Cowell papers, 1982-1995., Correspondence, speeches, and books of Susan Cowell, Vice President of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
    - 5780/113. Wilbur Daniels papers, 1967-1973., Contains files maintained by Wilbur Daniels while working as Associate General Counsel in the Legal Department, Assistant to the President, Director of the Master Agreements Department (1965-19??), Vice President, and Executive Vice-President. The bulk of the files pertain to the negotiation of agreements with companies and associations in the 1960s and 1970s.
    - 5780/155. Wilbur Daniels papers, 1977-1985., Contains records of Wilbur Daniels relating to General Executive Board meetings and ILGWU conventions, including reports, correspondence, notes and planning documents. Also included are some correspondence President Sol Chaikin and materials relating to his retirement in 1986.
    - 5780/084. Wilbur Daniels papers, 1965-1987., Contains records of Wilbur Daniels from his tenure as Director of the Master Agreements Department, Vice President, and Executive Vice President. Includes records relating to General Executive Board meetings, ILGWU conventions, and administrative matters. Files from the Master Agreements Department contain agreements, arbitration cases, bargaining demands, clippings, correspondence, constitution clauses, legal documents, mediation notices, miscellaneous photographs, negotiations, notes, settlements, and wage standards.
    - 5780/190. Joseph Good papers, [1977-1987.], Contains records of Joseph Good, including correspondence, briefs, contracts, and other materials relating to Good’s work as Associate General Counsel of the ILGWU.
    - 5780/199. Murray Gross papers, [1948-1982.], This collection contains the papers of Murray Gross, including correspondence, newspaper clippings and other printed material.
    - 5780/199 AV. Murray Gross audio-visual materials, 1950-1979., This collection contains audio recordings by or about Murray Gross, as well as records produced by the ILGWU New York Cloak Joint Board and Labor Arts.
    - 5780/199 MB. Murray Gross memorabilia, This collection contains citations, awards, and other memorabilia of Murray Gross.